Nathan Smith - Senior full stack developer

http://nathansmithdeveloper.com

Phone: 027 214 1615

Email: nathansmithdeveloper@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathan-smith-4061164a/

INTRODUCTION

I am currently working in the field of web, app and software development. I work in both the front end and back end. I have a post graduate in computer science from The University of Waikato.

I'm interested in web trends, technology, fashion and playing the guitar. I know a range of programming languages/frameworks including Javascript, React, React Native, TypeScript and NodeJS.

I try my best when tackling a project, but I also try to plan the best way to complete the tasks. I code the application as my job entails but I also think about the overall architecture, best coding standards and how much time I have available.

My job requires a mix of creativity and logic - building the usability and experience of an application whilst adhering to best practices and project timings.

QUALIFICATIONS

The University of Waikato

- In 2010 I successfully completed my Bachelor of Science majoring in Computer Science, specialising in applied computing.
- In 2012 I successfully completed my post graduate in Computer Science.

SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

Front end languages

Javascript, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, JSON, YAML

Front end frameworks

React, React Native, Expo, Capacitor, Bootstrap

Front end testing

Vitest, Jest, Playwright, react-testing-library, TDD, Storybook

Backend development

Node JS, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase

AWS services

Lambda, DynamoDB, SNS, SQS, EventBridge, API gateway, SSM, S3, CDK, Cognito, Route53

Code automation and tooling

npm, pnpm, Yarn, Vite, Webpack, eslint, prettier

Workflow and dev op tools

Git, BitBucket, Circle CI, Docker, Jira, Appflow, Trello, Basecamp, Evernote, Slack, Command Line, Windows & Mac

Design

UX, UI, mobile, Sketch, Figma, Photoshop

Tracking and marketing

Google Analytics, Campaign Monitor, Salesforce, Marketo, Hubspot, email template development

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

OFX

Employment: Current

Position: Senior software engineer

Here at OFX I am a fullstack engineer overseeing both the front end and back end.

We have a Typescript tech stack, React in the front end and Node JS in the back end. We use Vite for the build, open API for API first development and AWS CDK in a monorepo based structure. We also use AWS services extensively such as Dynamo, Lambda and SQS. OFX is based on a serverless structure.

OFX is an application which allows making payments easier than ever. You can make a payment, deposit or withdrawal in Australia and it will settle instantly. You can also make low cost, same day payments to 180+ other countries.

n3 Hub

Employment: 2018 - 2021

Position: Senior developer

At n3 Hub I led the front end scope of our products and services. We worked on a number of apps for some big clients such as Westpac and IAG.

I used ES6 React along with Material UI for building our apps. Our RESTful API was built with Python which I worked on from time to time. We worked with a lot of data so we had to consume our API using best RESTful practices, while also considering client side and server side web performance.

I was in charge of the design, UX and UI of our biggest apps. This extended my role and meant I was involved in multiple steps of the product life cycle.

I have worked on an app/website project, which involves building a website and a native app in both iOS and Android, using the same code base. I used React Native to build this project.

I worked with a core team of back end developers, front end developers and dev ops. The wider team includes a mix of marketing, data analysts and management.

Goodfolk

Employment: 2015 - 2018

Position: Senior web developer

At Goodfolk my role was development on websites and applications. I was involved with client meetings, I wrote technical specifications and I carried out user testing.

I had a leadership role as I helped other web developers with proper code structure, setting up workflows and helping them with best development practices. I helped bring Trello and Slack into the business, which improved our communication and organisation of work. I worked with a range of designers, developers and managers.

I worked in the ASP.NET space collaborating with back end developers, on a couple of projects for Auckland Council. I was required to integrate front end logic into .NET templates and familiarise myself with the back end logic.

I have used Angular JS in a number of projects, making use of its controllers, directives, routing and services. I always made sure to adhere to the proper Angular file structure. I have used Nunjucks with Gulp to create static websites. With other projects I used Javascript with ES6, then transpiled it to ES5 with Babel to work in modern browsers. I got familiar with (at the time) new ES6 features such as arrow functions, template literals and spread operators.

APN NZ/ NZME.

Employment: 2014 - 2015

Position: Front end lead

I was the lead of a front end team. My main responsibilities were to develop future proof front end solutions and represent the team to the wider business. I was in charge of work reports and tracking how my team was going. I worked on various projects: NZ Herald regional websites (9 in total) and NZ Herald rugby. I wrote HTML, CSS and Javascript/jQuery.

I had to create a clean file structure for the CSS for each of the regional publications, making sure they didn't conflict with one another. For NZ Herald rugby I had to write a lot of custom Javascript, as we weren't using a Javascript framework. I had to work with data feeds from various sources and AJAX them into the website.

APN NZ

Employment: 2012 – 2014

Position: Front end web developer

I worked primarily on maintaining and updating The New Zealand Herald website. I worked on the Listener website redesign, using HTML, CSS and PHP. I worked on other APN websites such as Women's Weekly and Dream Team.

I worked with front end technologies: LESS, SASS, Javascript, jQuery and HTML5. I used Git for version control. I used the backend languages Coldfusion and PHP. I used both Windows and Mac operating systems.

Anvil Labs

Employment: 2011 – 2012

Position: Web developer

I worked on multiple sites as a member of a small team where my main responsibilities were on the front end. I used the Django framework which included using the built in templating system and back end Python work.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.